<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Arjun Mahishi</title>
    <link>https://arjunmahish.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Arjun Mahishi</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://arjunmahish.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://arjunmahish.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 11:44:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arjunmahish.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rewriting my existing neovim config in lua</title>
      <link>https://arjunmahish.com/vim-adventures/vimscript-to-lua-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 11:44:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arjunmahish.com/vim-adventures/vimscript-to-lua-migration/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to rewrite my neovim config in Lua for a really long time. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know why. Just wanted to do it. Lua has a more sane and intuitive syntax compared to vimscript. So, it ends up being easier to maintain, refactor and extend. Plus, I think the entire neovim community is moving forward in this direction. I am hearing good things about vimscript in vim9, but maybe that will be an opportunity for another such blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prettify JSON in Vim</title>
      <link>https://arjunmahish.com/vim-adventures/prettify-json/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 19:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arjunmahish.com/vim-adventures/prettify-json/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR au filetype json nmap &amp;lt;leader&amp;gt;f :%!jq &amp;#39;.&amp;#39; %&amp;lt;CR&amp;gt; Challenge If you have ever opened a large auto-generated JSON file, you probably would have wanted to pull your hair out. To be able to read it easily, you would have to copy the whole thing, open an online JSON formatting tool, paste it, get the formatted output and read it.
I knew that jq can be used on CLI to format JSON, so I wanted to use that from within vim to do the formatting and skip the above circus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initialization Loop in Golang</title>
      <link>https://arjunmahish.com/posts/initialization-loop-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arjunmahish.com/posts/initialization-loop-golang/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, I was writing a program in Go and ran into an initialization loop. I was able to quickly fix it with 1 google search which landed on this StackOverflow question. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t explain what an init loop is and why it occurs. So, this post is an attempt to explain the what and the why.
Example of an init loop package main var ( globalFunc = func1 ) func main() {} func func1() { func2() } func func2() { globalFunc() } Trying to compile the above code will give you this error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tapping into the system clipboard</title>
      <link>https://arjunmahish.com/vim-adventures/tapping-into-system-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 10:45:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arjunmahish.com/vim-adventures/tapping-into-system-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR vmap &amp;lt;leader&amp;gt;y &amp;#34;*y nmap &amp;lt;leader&amp;gt;p &amp;#34;*p Challenge Copying text to and from vim and the outside world is a pain in the ass. This is because vim&amp;rsquo;s default register where it stores text copied with y is scoped only to that perticular vim session.
Solution Add this to your vimrc/init.vim:
vmap &amp;lt;leader&amp;gt;y &amp;#34;*y nmap &amp;lt;leader&amp;gt;p &amp;#34;*p This is basically mapping &amp;lt;leader&amp;gt; + y to run the &amp;quot;*y command. The &amp;quot; tells vim which register to use, * is the register that is shared with the system clipboard and y is the action (copy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Golang&#39;s Stringer tool</title>
      <link>https://arjunmahish.com/posts/golang-stringer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arjunmahish.com/posts/golang-stringer/</guid>
      <description>Straight from the documentation:
 Stringer is a tool to automate the creation of methods that satisfy the fmt.Stringer interface. Given the name of a (signed or unsigned) integer type T that has constants defined, stringer will create a new self-contained Go source file implementing:
func (t T) String() string The file is created in the same package and directory as the package that defines T. It has helpful defaults designed for use with go generate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test-driven development with Golang</title>
      <link>https://arjunmahish.com/posts/tdd-with-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arjunmahish.com/posts/tdd-with-golang/</guid>
      <description>Testing — An activity hated by most human beings Testing is an investigation done to make sure that the code we have written is reliable and meets the given requirements. The most common way to test code is to write unit tests for different units of the codebase. This makes it easy to isolate the bugs. All of the software development processes include testing as an integral part. The one we are going to talk about today is called Test Driven Development or TDD in short.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
